<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ahmad Hamze Homepage</title>
    <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ahmad Hamze Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://AhmadHamze.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Recursion with Memoization</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/algorithmics/memoization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/algorithmics/memoization/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we will go over an example of recursion and how we can use something called memoization to increase the speed of the code.
The Fibonacci Sequence If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of it, it&amp;rsquo;s quite simple, just start with two numbers 0 and 1, and add them together to get the next number in the sequence (yeah, that&amp;rsquo;ll be 1 once again).
Now add the new number with the one just before it to obtain the next number, so 1 + 1 and that is 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppeteer vs Selenium</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/automation/puppeteer-vs-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/automation/puppeteer-vs-selenium/</guid>
      <description>This blog is for learning purposes only, you can find the complete code on my Github go there to find the instructions necessary to run the code. Introduction  In a previous blogI created a selenium bot that performs the 10fastfingers typing speed, it scored 960 WPM.
This code was far from perfect, I did it quickly without taking into consideration the best performance that could be achieved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Speed Test</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/automation/selenium-speed-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/automation/selenium-speed-test/</guid>
      <description>This blog is for learning purposes only, you can find the complete code on my Github go there to find the instructions necessary to run the code. Background  The first time I ever used Selenium, I had to type a string into a search bar. Doing so, I couldn&#39;t see if a string was typed at all, to the point where I thought maybe it doesn&#39;t actually type words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storybook with React</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/react/storybook-trivia-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/react/storybook-trivia-quiz/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I will be showing how to use Storybook with React and talk a bit about its benefits.
I have used Storybook during my first job as a frontend developer, and I enjoyed every moment of it.
What is Storybook Here&amp;rsquo;s a description from the official website
 Storybook is an open source tool for building UI components and pages in isolation. It streamlines UI development, testing, and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A React Typescript Trivia Quiz</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/react/trivia-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/react/trivia-quiz/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple React + TypeScript + Storybook application, it&amp;rsquo;s a trivia quiz where the user answers a question and when all the questions are finished, they can see their score and the correct answers.
In this blog, I will go over the most important parts of the code, which you can find here.
Handling the data received from the API The code is in api/quizz-api.ts.
The first thing to do is to create a type that handles the response returned by the API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Earthquakes Locations on a Map</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a data visualization program made using processing.py, I made it a few years ago, however, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great program that deserves recognition.
You can find the code and the data used here.
Data The program uses a csv file containing 2000 locations of earthquakes (longitude and latitude), the magnitude of the earthquakes, and the name of the place where they occurred (a string). Here is the source of the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A live pictionary using websockets</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/pictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/pictionary/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a project that uses websockets to create a drawing on a page and copy this drawing to another page instantly.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of websockets before, here&amp;rsquo;s the main idea:
  You send data from your browser to a server using a &amp;ldquo;socket&amp;rdquo; which is a real-time connection that can send data back and forth.
  There is another computer that is connected to the server and will receive the data from it also using a socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first C&#43;&#43; console application</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/c&#43;&#43;-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/c&#43;&#43;-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Matrix calculator for two by two and three by three real matrices This is a project that I did around three years ago, just after I finished taking my very first comprehensive programming course, it was about the C++ language.
Back then I knew that there are many better options to do matrix calculation, mostly using the Python Numpy library. I also knew that there are many C++ libraries that provide matrix calculation, most notably Eigen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From My First Web Dev Job</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/opinion/first-react-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/opinion/first-react-job/</guid>
      <description>Recently I started a web development job as a front-end developer, here are a few things I learned so far.
1. Make sure to have the correct working environment As you might know, preparing the development environment is an essential step when you start a new project. In my case, the team decided to use Nix for package management (it&amp;rsquo;s awesome). The first problem I faced is that I am using Windows, and to be able to use nix on Windows you have to use WSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice to my past self</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/opinion/advice-to-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/opinion/advice-to-myself/</guid>
      <description>Advice to my past self regarding programming In this blog, I talk about a few things that I wish somebody told me back when I started learning to program by myself, I hope you can benefit from this if you&amp;rsquo;re also new to programming.
1. Talk to real programmers who know what they&amp;rsquo;re doing Getting into the world of programming is quite easy, all you have to do is own a laptop, watch YouTube videos and try to build programs yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating pi</title>
      <link>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/estimating-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AhmadHamze.github.io/posts/estimating-pi/</guid>
      <description>Using the Monte-Carlo simulation to estimate the value of &amp;#x03C0;First of all, let&#39;s talk briefly about what is a Monte-Carlo simulation.
Simply put, it is a computational method that uses a large number of random samples to obtain a result. It is used in awide range of disciplines like mathematics, computer graphics, and physical sciences.In this blog, we will see how we can use this method to estimate the value of the mathematical constant \( \pi \).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
